<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gennaro Calendo&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Gennaro Calendo&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Gennaro Calendo</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Create Krona Plot from Qiime2 Artifacts</title>
      <link>/2019/10/06/2019-10-06-create-krona-plot-from-qiime2-artifacts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/10/06/2019-10-06-create-krona-plot-from-qiime2-artifacts/</guid>
      <description>Krona is a wonderful tool for interactively visualizing metagenomic samples. If you are using Qiime2 however, shaping your data into a format that can be used by Krona is not entirely straight-forward. Below, I hope to explain my workflow for creating Krona charts derived from a Qiime2 workflow. I will use the example files from the Qiime2 Moving Pictures Tutorial to show how a krona chart can be constructed from these QIIME2 artifacts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Estimating K-mer Probabilities</title>
      <link>/2019/10/06/2019-10-06-estimating-k-mer-probabilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/10/06/2019-10-06-estimating-k-mer-probabilities/</guid>
      <description>Estimating k-mer probabilities Disclaimer: This was a challenge problem set forth in Bioinformatics Algorithms An Active Learning Approach by Phillip Compeau and Pavel Pevzner (2018). I borrow heavily from their examples.
The Problem What is the probability that a some k-mer will appear at least \(t\) times as a sub-string of a random string of length \(N\) composed of alphabet \(A\)?
For example, what is the probability that some 9-mer appears 3 or more times in a random DNA string of length 500?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding DnaA Boxes in Salmonella Enterica</title>
      <link>/2019/10/06/2019-10-06-finding-dnaa-boxes-in-salmonella-enterica/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/10/06/2019-10-06-finding-dnaa-boxes-in-salmonella-enterica/</guid>
      <description>I have been working through Bioinformatics Algorithms: An Active Learning Approach by Compeau and Pevzner and wanted to try out some of the Challenge Problems. This challenge problem is finding the DnaA boxes in Salmonella enterica.
DnaA boxes are short segments within bacterial ori (origins of replication) which DnaA binds to. DnaA then instructs the cell to begin replication at that location. Get the sequence
The first step in this problem is just getting the sequence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Powerlifting EDA</title>
      <link>/2019/10/06/2019-10-06-open-powerlifting-eda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/10/06/2019-10-06-open-powerlifting-eda/</guid>
      <description>Stronger by Science I recently read this blog post by Greg Nuckols on his blog, Stronger by Science, which compares trends in strength improvments across powerlifters for the last 30 or so years. The main points of the article are all really interesting but what interested me the most was the dataset he used: The OpenPowerlifting dataset.
The OpenPowerlifting project:
 …aims to create a permanent, accurate, convenient, accessible, open archive of the world’s powerlifting data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/page/about/</guid>
      <description>About I am a recent graduate of a Master’s program in bioinformatics and general biological data science enthusiast. Currently, I am working as an Associate Bioinformatics Scientist at the Corriell Institute for Medical Research. I plan on using this blog to document my learning experience as I continue to grow and learn new things about bioinformatics and programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/page/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/page/contact/</guid>
      <description>Send me an email at: jcalendo@gmail.com</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>